BRIGHT OGHOR

No 3, rumuekini road, Port Harcourt, Rivers 500101 +234 8148185691 oghorbright1@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Experienced Software Engineer and Startup Owner with a strong background in backend development, Python, and C programming. Proven track record in teaching and mentoring, building real-world web applications, and leading teams. My goal is to bring my diverse experience, technical expertise of over 4 years, and passion for mentorship to a challenging role.

Skills

- C
- Git
- Bootstrap
- CSS
- Django
- JavaScript
- Multitasking
- · Requirements gathering
- Shell Scripting
- Customer relations
- Mongo DB

- Python
- SQL
- HTML
- Flask
- Supervise programmers
- Node.js
- Project coordination
- Collaboration
- Bash
- Creative thinking
- API development

Experience

Founder & Software Engineer Bwave ICT - PortHarcourt, Rivers

Jun 2022 - Current

- Established and spearheaded Bwave ICT, a startup dedicated to providing comprehensive education in software engineering, C, Python, problem-solving, and critical thinking.
- Adhered to best python practices and coding standards to develop high-quality software solutions, leading to positive reviews from both developers and end users.
- Single handedly developed and deployed a full-stack functional web application from scratch for Bwave ICT with Flask, Javscript and MySQL, enabling course applications, payments, client communication, blog posts, and admin functionalities within the duration of 2 months, thereby leading to a rise of over 70 new students and over 100 website visits daily.
- Personally crafted the frontend with a user-friendly UI, showcasing versatility and proactive problem-solving abilities.
- Recorded and published free and premium tutorial videos on YouTube explaining complicated programming topics, web projects and software engineering topics.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to create successful systems meeting unique client needs, including building and deploying a registration portal using Django for the backend and JavaScript for the frontend.

- Trained end-users on the functions and optimal use of new software applications, resulting in an enhanced user experience and improved Client-Developer relationship.
- Mentored junior developers and intern students on code best practices.
- Provided support and continous learning guide for graduate students, interns and junior developers
- Actively participated in code reviews, providing constructive feedback to junior developers.
- Merged pull requests, ensuring code quality and adherence to project standards.
- Demonstrated mentorship by guiding junior developers and intern through the Git pull request process.

Software Engineer

Nov 2022 - May 2023

Codeytek - Remote

- Prepared and delivered courses in C, Git and Python for students.
- Implemented advanced security features at Codeytek, enhancing website security and preventing SQL injection by leveraging third-party solutions, resulting in a faster development time and more beneficial outcome
- Trained students to gain mastery of various programming languages such as C, Git, Python, MySQL, Flask, Django and API's

Software Engineer

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

Today FM Radio - Port Harcourt, Rivers

- Single-handedly designed and developed a fully functional full-stack website application using Express.js and Node.js for Today FM Radio.
- Implemented secure storage of detailed information for radio workers in the database using graphql, ensuring smooth management and storage of user details.
- Implemented password hashing and recovery features, ensuring the security of the admin portal in the SQL database.
- Trained end-users on functions and optimal use of new software applications.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Business Studies

Certificate: Software Engineering

Alx software engineering

Certificate: computer science

Harvard CS50 X

Certificate: Web Development

Sep 2021

Rivers State ICT

Awards

- Best Project Presentation, Rivers State ICT 2021
- Best Project Implementation, Rivers State ICT 2021
- Nominee for Mentor of the Year, Techrity 2023
- Nominee for Social Impact Icon, Techrity 2023

Accomplishments

- Mentored students who secured scholarships for Ph.D. studies in computer science abroad.
- Graduates of Bwave ICT are now employed at prestigious organizations including The Room, ALX, Go My Code, and Cinfores.
- Consistently recognized as the top performer and achiever in all learning and working experiences.
- Mentored over 1000 Software engineering students in the duration of a year
- Over 150,000 views on YouTube channel with +6,700 subscribers.
- Over 1,200 followers on GitHub.

Links

- GitHub: http://github.com/brightdaniel
- YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/@BwaveICT
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brightdaniel
- Website: https://www.bwaveict.pro